I'm Jake O'Neill creator of animagraphs
我是杰克·奥尼尔动画的创造者
and this is how a P51 Mustang works
这就是P51野马的工作原理
I've chosen the definitive p51d model
我选择了权威的p51d型号
which entered service in late 1943
1943年底投入使用
as a very capable all around fighter
作为一个非常有能力的全能战士
and long range bomber escort
和远程轰炸机护航
that helped grant Allied forces air superiority
帮助盟军获得空中优势
let's start with the frame and outer skin
让我们从框架和外皮开始
hundreds of panels
数百个面板
are riveted to a supporting structure
铆接在支撑结构上
called the airframe
叫做机身
these parts are mostly made of aluminum for strong
这些零件大多由铝制成，用于坚固
yet lightweight construction
轻质结构
sturdy beams and cross braces support the engine
坚固的横梁和交叉支撑支撑发动机
hardened steel armor plates in front
前面的硬化钢板
and behind the cockpit
在驾驶舱后面
offer some Protection to the pilot from enemy gunfire
保护飞行员免受敌人的炮火袭击
the fuselage has long
机身长了
rungs that extend the length of the frame
延伸框架长度的横档
and horizontal formers
和水平成型机
ribs and spars make up the wing structure
肋和翼梁构成了机翼结构
with smaller stringers for additional support
用较小的纵梁提供额外的支持
aluminum frame components get their yellow coloring
铝框架组件得到黄色
from a special protective coating
来自特殊的保护涂层
exterior parts might have a range of different finishes
外部零件可能有一系列不同的饰面
designed to smooth out bodywork and rivet bumps
旨在抚平车身和铆钉凸起
for a faster and better handling airplane
为了更快更好地操纵飞机
landing gear and steering
起落架和转向
the main landing gear is controlled by a hydraulic
主起落架由液压控制
actuator
执行器
a separate actuator manages the clamshell doors
一个单独的执行器管理翻盖门
a moving lock pin
移动锁销
secures the mechanism in place when the gear is down
当齿轮放下时将机械装置固定到位
there's a shock absorber inside the support arm
支撑臂里有减震器
and a brake in each wheel
每个轮子上都有刹车
the pilot can steer the plane while grounded
飞行员可以在停飞时操纵飞机
by pressing the left or right rudder pedals
通过按左或右方向舵踏板
which also engages corresponding wheel brakes
它还与相应的车轮制动器接合
the rear landing gear mechanism is more complex
后起落架机构更复杂
the assembly is retractable
组件是可伸缩的
just like the main landing gear
就像主起落架一样
however the rear wheel can operate in locked mode
然而，后轮可以在锁定模式下运行
which links its rotation to the airplane's rudder
它的旋转与飞机的方向舵相连
as the rudder rotates
随着方向舵旋转
cables tighten in turn
电缆依次拧紧
turning the wheel left or right
左转或右转
cables pass through a spring loaded tensioner
电缆穿过弹簧加载的张紧器
so they remain taut
所以它们保持绷紧
but can still move with the rear shock absorber
但仍然可以与后减震器一起移动
engine
发动机
the p51d is powered by a Packard V1650 Marlin engine
p51d由Packard V1650 Marlin发动机提供动力
it has 12 cylinders in a 60 degree V formation
它有12个气缸在60度V编队
and produces 1,400 horsepower
并产生1400马力
with a top speed of 430 plus miles per hour
最高时速430多英里
air enters through an intake under the nose section
空气通过鼻子下面的进气口进入
and is forced through a large
并被迫通过一个大的
centrifugal or circular shaped supercharger
离心式或圆形增压器
engine cooling is handled with a radiator
发动机冷却由散热器处理
located just behind the wings under the fuselage
位于机身下方的机翼后面
the low hanging scoop
低垂的勺子
is separate from the airplane body
与机身分离
to capture cleaner air
捕捉更清洁的空气
that's further from the turbulence causing
那离引起的湍流更远
exterior features
外观特征
and propeller air
和螺旋桨空气
the placement also allows a longer duct
该位置还允许更长的管道
to take advantage of the Meredith effect
利用梅雷迪思效应
where hot air from the radiator's normal function
散热器正常功能的热风
can be used to produce thrust
可以用来产生推力
recovering as much as
恢复到
90 percent of the drag caused by the radiator scoop
散热器勺造成的90%的阻力
the radiator exhaust port
散热器排气口
has an adjustable flap to regulate outflow
有一个可调节的皮瓣来调节流出
a separate engine oil cooler with its own exhaust flap
带有自己排气挡板的单独发动机油冷却器
also resides in the scoop
也驻留在勺子中
an engine oil tank is mounted to the firewall
发动机油箱安装在防火墙上
a front mounted tank holds circulating radiator fluid
前安装的水箱容纳循环散热器流体
exhaust exits through short angled nozzles
通过短角度喷嘴的排气出口
fuel tanks in each wing hold 92 gallons each
两翼的油箱各能装92加仑
with an additional
附加
85 gallon fuselage tank behind the cockpit
驾驶舱后面85加仑机身油箱
optional drop tanks
可选水箱
can be mounted to the underside of each wing
可以安装在每个机翼的下侧
at 110 gallons each
每人110加仑
pushing the total fuel capacity to a whopping
将总燃料容量推到惊人的水平
489 gallons
489加仑
with a resulting range of 1,650 miles
结果射程为1650英里
a fighter aircraft
一架战斗机
with the range to reach far into enemy territory
射程远至敌方领土
proved to be a major game changer in the war effort
被证明是战争努力中的一个主要游戏规则改变者
propeller
螺旋桨
the propeller is connected directly to the engine
螺旋桨直接连接到发动机
through a relatively simple gear set
通过相对简单的齿轮组
there is no transmission or gear shift
没有变速器也没有换挡
like you'd find in almost any land vehicle
就像你在任何陆地车辆中发现的那样
instead blade pitch can be controlled
相反，叶片间距可以控制
for example at takeoff
例如在起飞时
the blades are angled
刀片有角度
perpendicular to the airplane
垂直于飞机
for a strong forward pull
以获得强大的向前拉力
in little to zero existing air flow
现有的气流几乎为零
while cruising at speed however
然而，在高速巡航时
that same pitch would create a barrier
同样的音高会造成障碍
causing drag and slowing forward movement
造成阻力并减慢前进速度
so the blades are angled more in line
所以刀片的角度更直
with the direction of travel
与行进方向
armaments
军备
there are six Browning
有六个布朗宁
50 caliber machine guns mounted in the wings
机翼上装着50口径机枪
with three on each side
两边各有三个
they're controlled
他们被控制了
by a stick mounted trigger which when activated
通过安装在棍子上的扳机，当激活时
fires all guns simultaneously
同时发射所有火炮
ammo capacity is 1,880 rounds
弹药容量是1880发
with a fire rate of about 30 rounds per second
每秒发射30发子弹
with all six guns firing together
六支枪同时开火
that's about 30 seconds of total firing time
总共只有30秒的发射时间
there's no cockpit indicator for rounds remaining
驾驶舱没有剩余子弹的指示器
a camera mounted in each wing
安装在每个机翼上的相机
can be set to turn on when guns are fired
可以设置为开枪时打开
to record the result
记录结果
a single
单曲
removable bomb rack
可拆卸炸弹架
can be fitted to the underside of each wing
可以安装在每个机翼的下侧
to carry 100 250 or 500 pound bombs
携带100 250或500磅的炸弹
alternatively
可选择地
these racks can carry dropable fuel tanks
这些机架可以携带可滴油箱
6 rockets can also be loaded
还可以装载6枚火箭
with three on each wing
两翼各有三个
or 10 total rockets when the bomb rack is not in use
或者炸弹架不使用时总共10枚火箭
cockpit
驾驶舱
these planes were designed for technical war operations
这些飞机是为战争技术作战而设计的
and were not expected to be comfortable
并且不被期望感到舒适
as a first priority
作为第一要务
some pilots reported
一些飞行员报告说
having to be lifted out of the cockpit
必须被抬出驾驶舱
after deep range missions
在执行远距离任务后
in such cramped quarters
在这么狭窄的地方
controls and gauges cover every surface
控制和仪表覆盖每一个表面
leaving space only for the pilot's body
只给飞行员的身体留出空间
and bulky flight gear
和笨重的飞行装备
starting from the left side of the cockpit
从驾驶舱左侧开始
there's a flare gun case and a flare gun mounting tube
有一个信号枪盒和一个信号枪安装管
that extends through the plane to the exterior
从平面延伸到外部
below that a wing flap control lever sets the position
在其下方，一个襟翼控制杆设置位置
of the main wing flaps
主襟翼
a set of dials controls various trim tabs on the rudder
一组表盘控制方向舵上的各种配平标签
ailerons and elevators
副翼和升降机
for example
例如
if more fuel gets used in one wing tank than the other
如果一个机翼油箱的燃料比另一个多
the airplane may become unbalanced and
飞机可能会变得不平衡
pull in unwanted directions
往不需要的方向拉
the appropriate trim tab can be adjusted
可以调整适当的修剪标签
to counter the unwanted attitude
对抗不必要的态度
so the pilot doesn't have to
这样飞行员就不用
fight against the controls
对抗控制
to constantly balance the craft
不断平衡工艺
the radiator and oil cooler switches
散热器和油冷却器开关
control the previously shown exhaust
控制前面显示的排气
flap positions for those systems
这些系统的襟翼位置
also on this panel
也在这个面板上
a landing light switch
着陆灯开关
for lights that fold out of the main landing gear bay
用于从主起落架舱折叠出来的灯
and a switch for the left side cockpit light
还有驾驶舱左侧灯的开关
the landing gear lever is down by the pilot's left leg
起落架的操纵杆被飞行员的左腿压住了
as well as the left wing fuel tank gauge
以及左翼油箱仪表
the bomb salvo lever mechanically releases bombs
炸弹齐射杆机械释放炸弹
as opposed to the electrically activated button
而不是电启动按钮
on the stick
在棍子上
the fuel to air mixture
燃料与空气的混合物
propeller RPM
螺旋桨每1k展现的收入
and engine throttle controls are grouped together
和发动机油门控制组合在一起
the propeller RPM lever setting
螺旋桨每1k展现的收入杠杆设置
attempts to maintain constant
试图保持不变
propeller rotational speed
螺旋桨转速
automatically altering things like
自动更改诸如
engine throttle or propeller blade pitch to do so
发动机节气门或螺旋桨叶片间距这样做
the propeller and the air around it functions
螺旋桨和它周围的空气起作用
something like an automatic transmission does in a car
就像汽车里的自动变速器一样
and in the same way
以同样的方式
a car's engine RPMs
汽车发动机转速
aren't always directly related to the actual speed
并不总是与实际速度直接相关
the car may be traveling
车可能在行驶
so for an airplane
所以对于飞机来说
controlling propeller speed
控制螺旋桨转速
is the best way to control airspeed
是控制空速的最好方法
moving to the pilot's forward view
移动到飞行员的前方视野
we see the flight stick
我们看到飞行棒了
with a bomb release button on top
顶部有炸弹释放按钮
and the gun trigger at the front
和前面的枪扳机
generally speaking
一般来说
flight stick left or right movement will roll the plane
飞行棒向左或向右移动将使飞机滚动
stick forward or back movement alters the pitch
向前或向后移动会改变音高
the left and right rudder pedals manage yaw
左右舵踏板控制偏航
beyond the stick
超出常规
we see the fuel shut off lever
我们看到燃料关闭杆
and a fuel tank selector dial
和一个油箱选择表盘
the faring door
远门
emergency pull lever releases landing gear
紧急拉杆释放起落架
in case of a motorized malfunction
以防发生机动故障
once released
一旦释放
gear can be manually locked by yawing the plane left
齿轮可以通过飞机向左偏航手动锁定
or right
或对
a hydraulic pressure gauge is situated nearby
附近有一个液压压力表
a warning light above the emergency lever
应急杆上方的警示灯
indicates if landing gear doors are open
显示起落架门是否打开
separate warning lights indicate left
单独的警示灯指示左侧
and right landing gear lock status
和右起落架锁定状态
the various switches and knobs nearby
附近的各种开关和旋钮
control armament settings
控制军备设置
bombs can be released altogether or in a train
炸弹可以一起释放也可以在火车上释放
guns can be set as single fire
枪可以设置为单发火
burst or fully automatic
突发或全自动
the amount of rounds per burst can also be set
也可以设置每次爆发的回合数
with the corresponding dial
与相应的表盘
on the left of this panel
在这个面板的左边
there's the engine ignition switch
这是发动机点火开关
in the center the parking brake
在中间的驻车制动器
the left switch bank has supercharger boost control
左侧开关组具有增压器升压控制
and other engine specific settings
和其他引擎特定设置
on the right
在右边
the oxygen blinker moves with the pilot's breathing
氧气指示灯随着飞行员的呼吸而移动
to very accurately indicate oxygen consumption
非常准确地显示氧气消耗
with each breath
每一次呼吸
pilots need specific oxygen indicators
飞行员需要特定的氧气指示器
due to the dangers of consuming too much
由于消耗过多的危险
or too little oxygen
或者氧气太少
which can cause confusion and pilot error
这可能会导致混淆和飞行员错误
a pressure gauge to the right
右边的压力表
indicates oxygen system pressure
表示氧气系统压力
the oxygen regulator controls flow to the pilot
氧气调节器控制流向飞行员
there are left and right
有左有右
positionable lights for illumination
可定位照明灯
the yellow line across the dashboard
仪表板上的黄线
separates flight control
分离飞行控制
related gauges into their own section
相关仪表进入自己的部分
from the left
从左边
we have the altimeter for altitude
我们有高度表
the airspeed indicator
空速指示器
the directional gyro and compass
定向陀螺仪和指南针
which are used together to maintain
它们一起使用来维护
a specific course of travel
特定行程
the bank and turn indicator
倾斜和转弯指示灯
shows the plane's current attitude
显示飞机目前的姿态
the artificial horizon indicates ground angle
人工地平线表示地面角度
relative to the plane
相对于平面
outside the white line there's the clock
白线外是时钟
a suction gauge to monitor vacuum pressure
用于监测真空压力的吸力计
since many of these gauges and instruments use
由于许多这些仪表和仪器使用
vacuum pressure differences to function
真空压差起作用
the manifold pressure gauge
歧管压力表
tracks internal engine pressure
跟踪发动机内部压力
the propeller might be turning at the same speed
螺旋桨可能以相同的速度转动
but requiring lots of engine force
但需要大量的发动机动力
so manifold pressure must be monitored
因此必须监控歧管压力
there's a coolant temperature gauge
有一个冷却剂温度计
a tachometer for engine RPMs
发动机转速计
a carburetor air temperature indicator
化油器空气温度指示器
to make sure the engine
以确保发动机
air intake stays within a reasonable range
进气保持在合理范围内
and an oil and fuel pressure gauge
以及机油和燃油压力表
turning to the pilot's right side
转向驾驶员右侧
we see electrical and radio equipment controls
我们看到电气和无线电设备控制
including an ammeter to monitor electrical current
包括一个电流表来监测电流
from the plane's generator
从飞机的发电机
there are switches for generator and battery disconnect
有发电机和电池断开开关
left and right gun heaters
左右枪加热器
and position lights
和位置灯
red green and amber
红绿和琥珀色
position lights on the underside of the right wing tip
右翼尖下侧的位置灯
can display codes
可以显示代码
to indicate friendly aircraft approach at night
指示友军飞机在夜间接近
light model P51 DS
轻型P51 DS
had a tail radar system to warn
有一个尾部雷达系统来警告
of aircraft behind the plane
飞机后面的飞机
a radio frequency tuner and headphone hook in
射频调谐器和耳机挂钩
sits beneath that
坐在那下面
the last couple modules are radio control units
最后几个模块是无线电控制单元
and an IFF system
和IFF系统
used to signal a friendly aircraft
用来向友军飞机发出信号
to external radar systems
到外部雷达系统
the right wing fuel tank gauge is on the floor
右翼油箱仪表在地板上
by the seat pan
在座位盘旁边
the canopy crank is also on this side
天篷曲柄也在这边
with an emergency release lever
带有紧急释放杆
just behind the pilot's left ear
就在飞行员的左耳后面
there's the fuselage fuel tank gauge
这是机身油箱仪表
various electronic devices
各种电子设备
including radio and radar modules
包括无线电和雷达模块
and behind that the oxygen tank storage bay
后面是氧气罐储藏室
coming back to the pilot's view we see the gun sight
回到飞行员的视角，我们看到了瞄准镜
a standard straight ahead sight
标准的直线瞄准镜
marked with the plus sign
用加号标记
and a compensating sight
和补偿视线
are projected from horizontal lenses
从水平镜头投射
onto a thin pane of angled glass
在一块薄玻璃上
the pilot sets the wingspan dial at the front
飞行员将翼展拨盘设置在前面
to correspond to the target's wingspan
来对应目标的翼展
measured in feet
以英尺为单位
a twist grip on the throttle
扭动油门
brings the compensating side's diamond ring
带来补偿方的钻石戒指
into an imaginary circle around the target's wings
在目标的翅膀周围形成一个假想的圆圈
this
这
combined with the center dot over the target's cockpit
与目标座舱上的中心点相结合
automatically calculates bullet range and arc
自动计算子弹射程和弧度
as both planes move through the air at speed
两架飞机在空中高速飞行
pilot
飞行员
during the era of the P51
在P51时代
regulations for pilots gear were
飞行员装备的规定是
a bit more open to individual preference
对个人偏好更开放一点
so I've put together a generalized equipment set
所以我组装了一套通用设备
the pilot wears a leather helmet
飞行员戴着皮头盔
with earphones built in
内置耳机
also a set of goggles
还有一套护目镜
and an oxygen mask
和氧气面罩
with a built in microphone
带内置麦克风
just above the breathing tube
就在呼吸管上方
the pilot wears a vest style yellow life preserver
飞行员穿着背心式黄色救生衣
parachute rigging straps
降落伞索具带
encircle the pilot's torso and legs
包围飞行员的躯干和腿
and extend to a parachute back pad
并延伸到降落伞背垫
that was often packed with first aid items
里面经常装满急救物品
and a one person life raft
和一个人的救生筏
the pilot's parachute
飞行员的降落伞
is packaged beneath the seat cushion
包装在座垫下面
all of these things
所有这些事情
are attached to the parachute rigging
连接到降落伞索具上
and follow the pilot in the event of a bailout
并在紧急援助的情况下跟随飞行员
the jacket and coveralls are either wool or cotton
夹克和工作服不是羊毛就是棉的
paired with warm leather gloves and boots
搭配保暖的皮手套和靴子